<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Interlock Rochester - Rochester's Hackerspace - Hardware, Programming, Projects, Uncategorized</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/hardware-programming-projects-uncategorized.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2014-06-24T22:07:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Raspberry Pi IP audio announcement: ippivox</title><link href="/raspberry-pi-ip-audio-announcement-ippivox.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-24T22:07:00-04:00</published><updated>2014-06-24T22:07:00-04:00</updated><author><name>dzho</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-06-24:/raspberry-pi-ip-audio-announcement-ippivox.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, you can ssh into your Raspberry Pi, even if you don't have any
HDMI-capable display equipment at hand.&amp;nbsp; The trick, though, is knowing
what IP address gets assigned to the Pi so that you know what to feed
into your ssh client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier, these pages addressed this problem &lt;a class="reference external" href="/raspberry-pi-macgyver.html"&gt;using …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, you can ssh into your Raspberry Pi, even if you don't have any
HDMI-capable display equipment at hand.&amp;nbsp; The trick, though, is knowing
what IP address gets assigned to the Pi so that you know what to feed
into your ssh client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier, these pages addressed this problem &lt;a class="reference external" href="/raspberry-pi-macgyver.html"&gt;using VNC to provide a
remote Raspberry Pi
display&lt;/a&gt;
(eg, from your laptop).&amp;nbsp; It's a good approach, well documented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternately, with a little bit of prep work, perhaps using the above
technique to get everything set up to start, you can program your Pi to
announce its IP address via audio using text-to-speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_1665&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot;
width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot;]&lt;img alt="earbuds" class="wp-image-1665 size-medium" src="/wp-uploads/2014/06/earbuds-300x225.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 225px;" /&gt; Much cheaper output than a HDMI-capable
monitor[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The essence of this trick is to install a text-to-speech program, create
a small script to extract the IP address, to pass that address to the
text-to-speech program, and then finally to configure the initialization
scripts to run the readout script shortly after booting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm working with a rev B Raspberry Pi running Raspbian, but the approach
should be generalizable to any distro for which a TTS package is
available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, set up the Raspberry Pi with keyboard, mouse, wired networking,
and video, either HDMI or analog.&amp;nbsp; If you use analog, you may need to
increase the font size considerably even to be able to read the screen.
Open a terminal and install festival:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;sudo &lt;span class="pre"&gt;apt-get&lt;/span&gt; install festival&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, if you haven't already done so, create a &lt;strong&gt;bin&lt;/strong&gt; directory in your
home directory to hold this and other small local scripts and programs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;mkdir ~/bin&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, open your favorite editor to create a small script file containing
the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;`` #!/usr/bin/bash /usr/bin/amixer cset numid=3 1 /sbin/ifconfig | /bin/grep -A3 eth0 | /bin/grep inet | /usr/bin/tr ':' ' ' | /usr/bin/cut -d-f 13 | /usr/bin/festival --tts``&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be careful if you try to copy-and-paste that that a) you get the
single-quotes carried over into the right place and b) that you don't
have any space or tab or other otherwise hard-to-see non-newline
whitespace characters at the end of the lines with backslashes. If
either error crops up, edit to fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(NB: ifconfig is a bit old school. Interlock HAM and rally enthusiast
HoopyCat points out that to be fully kids-these-days compliant, one
should use the &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;ip&lt;/tt&gt; command.)*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save the file as &lt;strong&gt;/home/pi/bin/ippixvox.sh&lt;/strong&gt; and give it execute
permissions with &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;chmod a+x /home/pi/bin/ippixvox.sh&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;You can now test it by typing&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;`` ~/bin/ippivox.sh``&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;into your terminal with a speaker or earphones plugged in. If you are
connected to a network (and if not, how did you get festival
downloaded?) you should hear the IPv4 address read off. If not, run
ifconfig to check to make sure you do have IPv4 address (&amp;quot;inet&amp;quot;)
assigned, and that it is assigned to eth0. If it's assigned to something
other than eth0, modify the script above to suit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Finally, to make this work at boot time, open the file&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;**
/etc/init.d/rc.local**&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in an editor and add at the very bottom this one line&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;/home/pi/bin/ippivox.sh&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save, reboot, and listen for the IP address to be read to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it works, then you can dispense with attaching a video output device
when it comes time to hack on the Pi in favor of just logging in from a
machine elsewhere on the same network using ssh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find it useful to play a short alert announcement before the IP
address is read. I also use a second TTS program, flite, both to give me
a second shot at hearing the IP and also in hopes that I'll be better
able to understand at least one of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My more lengthy approach to this is documented in the following github
gist:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gist.github.com/deejoe/ce7984f94b91bdb6b48e"&gt;https://gist.github.com/deejoe/ce7984f94b91bdb6b48e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks go Matt via the Raspberry Pi blog for this &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.raspberrypi-spy.co.uk/2013/06/raspberry-pi-command-line-audio/"&gt;tip on configuring
the
audio.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>