<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>A Pelican Blog - berticus</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/berticus.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2012-10-03T11:08:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>3D Digitized Humans</title><link href="/3d-humans-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-03T11:08:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-10-03T11:08:00+00:00</updated><author><name>berticus</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-10-03:/3d-humans-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="/wp-uploads/2012/10/markme.gif"&gt;&lt;img alt="image0" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1034" src="/wp-uploads/2012/10/markme.gif" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.theopencrowdproject.com/people/mark-from-rochester/"&gt;&lt;img alt="image1" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1036" src="/wp-uploads/2012/10/mark-from-rochester-208x300.jpg" style="width: 208px; height: 300px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've been tinkering lately with taking pictures for &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.theopencrowdproject.com/"&gt;the Open Crowd
Project&lt;/a&gt;, an effort to create a
3D printed crowd of humanoids. It really doesn't take much effort, nor
much equipment. You just submit a series of photos of your model (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.theopencrowdproject.com/participate/"&gt;photo
guidelines&lt;/a&gt;), upload
them to the project, and sit …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="/wp-uploads/2012/10/markme.gif"&gt;&lt;img alt="image0" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1034" src="/wp-uploads/2012/10/markme.gif" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.theopencrowdproject.com/people/mark-from-rochester/"&gt;&lt;img alt="image1" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1036" src="/wp-uploads/2012/10/mark-from-rochester-208x300.jpg" style="width: 208px; height: 300px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've been tinkering lately with taking pictures for &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.theopencrowdproject.com/"&gt;the Open Crowd
Project&lt;/a&gt;, an effort to create a
3D printed crowd of humanoids. It really doesn't take much effort, nor
much equipment. You just submit a series of photos of your model (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.theopencrowdproject.com/participate/"&gt;photo
guidelines&lt;/a&gt;), upload
them to the project, and sit back while fancy software (mostly &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.123dapp.com/catch"&gt;123D
Catch&lt;/a&gt;) and diligent humans
painstakingly render your likeness in bits and bytes and plastic blobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model shown here isn't their best work, as we provided sub-par
imagery for our first attempt. We're submitting some better shots now,
so we'll see if our process has improved enough to give some higher
resolution models. Once we're good to go and have this process down, you
should feel free to stop in sometime and get yourself digitized!&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Hacks/Hackers Rochester</title><link href="/hackshackers-rochester.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-02-02T10:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-02-02T10:45:00+00:00</updated><author><name>berticus</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-02-02:/hackshackers-rochester.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few Wednesdays ago, after a long and cozy day of working from home, I
decided to break my &amp;quot;never leave the house or have meaningful human
contact&amp;quot; rule, and I ventured out to the snowy tundra of Henrietta. The
threshold for this odd behavior is quite high, but I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few Wednesdays ago, after a long and cozy day of working from home, I
decided to break my &amp;quot;never leave the house or have meaningful human
contact&amp;quot; rule, and I ventured out to the snowy tundra of Henrietta. The
threshold for this odd behavior is quite high, but I just couldn't bring
myself to miss the first meeting of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.meetup.com/HackshackersROC/"&gt;Hacks/Hackers
Rochester&lt;/a&gt;, a local group
aiming to mush together journalists, programmers, technologists,
designers, and what-have-you, just to see what kind of nutty/useful
stuff results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/6726571927/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hacks &amp;amp; Hackers Rochester" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7152/6726571927_7fd2e9714b_z.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I get too far, I'll have you know that their next meeting is
Wednesday, February 15th (at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rit.edu/"&gt;RIT's&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rit.edu/innovationcenter/"&gt;Center for
Student Innovation&lt;/a&gt;), and you
can get at them on their &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.meetup.com/HackshackersROC/"&gt;meetup
group&lt;/a&gt;, or their &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/#!/hackshackersroc/"&gt;twittery
bits&lt;/a&gt;. If combining
technology and journalism sounds fun to you, you should stop by, because
it seemed like a bunch of smart and interesting people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok. For the rest of our time together, I'm fixin' to dump a few links on
you. I am not a journalist, nor a programmer, but I have been quite
interested in this area for some time, and hope to contribute – at the
very least – as a well-informed cheerleader, brainstormer, facilitator,
or village idiot. We'll see. Either way, maybe I can give interested
parties some ideas of what's possible/probable before the next meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="open-sesame"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Open Sesame&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Open&amp;quot; excites me. Open source software, open hardware designs, open
data, &amp;quot;free culture&amp;quot; in general. Fun things happen when information is
free and accessible. Maybe this first dawned on me when I saw the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://oakland.crimespotting.org/"&gt;Oakland Crimespotting site&lt;/a&gt;. By
now, everybody has seen a multitude of visualizations made by dumping
data on top of Google Maps. Back then it was pretty new and exciting.
What struck me most, at the time, was that the Oakland PD was publishing
this data to a public website, and in a format that was fairly easily
scrape-able and parse-able. Wow! Amazingly pedestrian, really, but for a
city or county government it seemed unthinkable (and still does,
apparently).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many municipalities are doing a decent job in this area nowadays. Some
have even progressed enough that sites like
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.everyblock.com/"&gt;EveryBlock&lt;/a&gt; have sprung up, taking these
public data feeds and massaging them into a format that mere mortals can
make sense of. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://data.baltimorecity.gov/"&gt;Baltimore has an open data
website&lt;/a&gt; that looks like it has lots
of useful info, in easy to digest formats. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://data.cityofchicago.org/"&gt;Chicago
too&lt;/a&gt;. I'm sure there are many
others... those were just the first two to pop up when I poked around
for &amp;quot;data dot blah blah dot gov&amp;quot; sites. There is no
data.cityofrochester.gov site, unfortunately. How do we make that
happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="dumpy-data"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dumpy Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, we rely on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.foia.gov/"&gt;FOIA&lt;/a&gt; requests for
information from local governments. Often times, these arrive in the
least convenient format possible, and they are likely full of sloppy and
inconsistent data. We're pretty lucky then, that after cleaning things
up, the D&amp;amp;C often shares this data with us on their
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://rocdocs.democratandchronicle.com/"&gt;RocDocs&lt;/a&gt; site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder if they know about &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/p/google-refine/"&gt;Google
Refine&lt;/a&gt;? Refine is &amp;quot;a power
tool for working with messy data, cleaning it up, transforming it from
one format into another, extending it with web services, and linking it
to databases like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.freebase.com/"&gt;Freebase&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;quot; If you're
dealing with cruddy data of any sort, you should check it out. It's a
bit of a weird install, running as a web server on your computer. Ask
your &lt;a class="reference external" href="/"&gt;local nerds&lt;/a&gt; if you're having
trouble... it's worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="community-data"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Community Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you can get it in a decent format, governments don't always have
the data you need. Or if they do, it might be stale by the time you can
get at it. There are some fun things happening in the world of open data
acquisition. Let's call it &amp;quot;open mapping&amp;quot;, although I'm sure there are
non-location-based projects I'm overlooking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, Google is changing the terms of service on their Maps product...
taking it out of &amp;quot;beta&amp;quot; status and reaching into your wallet for some
payback. If you have a certain amount of map views per day, it's no
longer free to use. Thankfully, all along, a large community of folks
have been creating their own street maps by compiling open government
data (TIGER files in the US), or by walking, biking, and driving routes
with a GPS logger and uploading their tracks.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.openstreetmap.org/"&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt; is the result, and
it's an amazing feat. Anybody can edit the map... so feel free to liken
it to the &amp;quot;Wikipedia of maps&amp;quot;, even though that probably makes some
people bristle. Not coincidentally, the resultant data is available
under a farily open license, and has thus been mixed and remixed into a
plenitude of other projects, products, and experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.opencyclemap.org/"&gt;OpenCycleMap&lt;/a&gt; builds upon
OpenStreetMap, and highlights cycling routes. It is rather sparse in the
US. I recently attended some public meetings on Rochester's bicycle
plan, featuring some large maps of city streets rated &amp;quot;A&amp;quot; through &amp;quot;F&amp;quot;
for bike safety. Perhaps that belongs on such a map, editable by all
those who actually ride the city streets and know that traffic volume
and speed are not the only relevant dimensions for such a grade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="/wp-uploads/2012/02/tilemill_screenshot.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image1" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-814" src="/wp-uploads/2012/02/tilemill_screenshot.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 389px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.openheatmap.com/"&gt;OpenHeatMap&lt;/a&gt; lets you upload a
spreadsheet of data and crank out a heat map on top of OpenStreetMap.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mapbox.com/"&gt;Mapbox&lt;/a&gt; is a bit more sophisticated, but costs
some money for hosted maps. No matter... the Mapbox developers have
released &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mapbox.com/tilemill/"&gt;TileMill&lt;/a&gt;, a gorgeous
application that lets you handcraft interactive maps yourself. It
requires a bit more knowhow, but I'm sure Hacks/Hackers has plenty of
that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The folks at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.safecast.org/"&gt;Safecast&lt;/a&gt; wanted to map
radiation levels following the Fukushima disaster in Japan, so they
cobbled together some GPS loggers and Geiger counters. After driving
around the country, they plopped the data on top of the OpenStreetMap.
This isn't child's play yet, but every day it's getting easier to bring
together the hardware and software needed to record data and make it
easily available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="a-brief-aside"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Brief Aside&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These radiation mappers weren't &amp;quot;traditional journalists&amp;quot;. Maybe it
wasn't even journalism or news. Whatever. It was really important info,
and I'll bet no reporter thought &amp;quot;I'll just go out and record that data,
instead of waiting by the phone for an official report&amp;quot;. I hope, after
hanging out at Hacks/Hackers, that mindset will change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Semi-related: Rochester has &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://rocwiki.org/Ginna_Nuclear_Power_Plant"&gt;a nuclear power
plant&lt;/a&gt; nearby, and
Interlock has a Geiger counter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/6190437602/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Geiger Counter" src="http://farm7.staticflickr.com/6145/6190437602_041ccdbf22_z.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(not a terribly well calibrated Geiger counter, admittedly)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some more thoughts on the future of local news and journalism, from
people much smarter and more cogent than I, I will simply link without
comment to some posts I've bookmarked from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ryansholin.com/2007/06/02/10-obvious-things-about-the-future-of-newspapers-you-need-to-get-through-your-head/"&gt;Ryan
Sholin&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jeffcroft.com/blog/2006/dec/08/selected-responses-times-future-newspapers/"&gt;Jeff
Croft&lt;/a&gt;,
and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.timporter.com/firstdraft/archives/000446.html"&gt;Tim
Porter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="burbling-infobrooks"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Burbling Infobrooks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If real-time info is needed, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pachube.com/"&gt;Pachube&lt;/a&gt; is a
free clearinghouse for data feeds. It's ridiculously easy to upload
sensor data to the site, whether it be temperature, weather, energy use,
and so on. Equally important, it's also easy to retrieve that
information as a regularly updated and well-documented stream. Would you
like to browse the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pachube.com/feeds?q=radiation"&gt;2700 available feeds tagged
&amp;quot;radiation&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; on Pachube?
Probably not. But it'd be a relatively simple task to create a program
that retrieves and maps them in an easy to digest format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some folks – mainly in New York City – weren't quite satisfied with the
current status quo of air quality monitoring. So they're &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://airqualityegg.wikispaces.com/"&gt;building their
own sensor network&lt;/a&gt; using open
platforms to measure and make the data available to anybody that wants
it, in real time. This stuff isn't too technically challenging nowadays.
We just need to pair up those with a need for info with the people who
know how to get this stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="too-long-still-reading"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Too Long; Still Reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's plenty more fun stuff happening in this area, but that's enough
to keep you occupied for a few hours a least. If – after you close all
your browser tabs – you still find your cravings unfulfilled, do &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.meetup.com/HackshackersROC/"&gt;join
us at the next meeting&lt;/a&gt;, or
fire away in the comments here. I'm sure we'll be able to fill up or
otherwise utilize your vast cranial resources. See you there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>BarCamp Plot-chester</title><link href="/barcamp-rochester.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-10-30T20:37:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-10-30T20:37:00+00:00</updated><author><name>berticus</name></author><id>tag:None,2011-10-30:/barcamp-rochester.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="/wp-uploads/2011/10/DSC_84671.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Interlock's BarCamp Table" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-665" src="/wp-uploads/2011/10/DSC_84671-1024x678.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is usually the case, Interlock managed to cajole/bribe the organizers
of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://barcamproc.org/"&gt;BarCamp Rochester&lt;/a&gt; into giving us a table
in the atrium, upon which we could set up our wares and lure in
unsuspecting geeks. The conference itself was really great, with lots of
interesting talks, and lots of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="/wp-uploads/2011/10/DSC_84671.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Interlock's BarCamp Table" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-665" src="/wp-uploads/2011/10/DSC_84671-1024x678.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is usually the case, Interlock managed to cajole/bribe the organizers
of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://barcamproc.org/"&gt;BarCamp Rochester&lt;/a&gt; into giving us a table
in the atrium, upon which we could set up our wares and lure in
unsuspecting geeks. The conference itself was really great, with lots of
interesting talks, and lots of attendees and traffic by our table.
Everybody seemed quite excited about the &amp;quot;Skeletonizing Carcasses with
Flesh-eating Beetles&amp;quot; talk, myself included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, we've had a slight lack of table-sized projects that moved,
made noise, or otherwise stimulated people to come talk to us and see
what Interlock is all about... but no longer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="/wp-uploads/2011/10/DSC_84971.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image1" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-666" src="/wp-uploads/2011/10/DSC_84971-1024x678.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After becoming a little obsessed with &lt;a class="reference external" href="{filename}/plottopotamus.rst"&gt;old pen
plotters&lt;/a&gt; over the
past few months, I decided I'd like to try assembling my own drawing
robot. The main goal, again, was to have something small, cool, and
interactive to attract folks at events where we have a table or booth.
So about a month ago, our journey started with destruction... one
printer and one printer/scanner gave their slightly non-functional lives
to this project. Anything slightly cool was saved, and of course the
precision rods, stepper motors, and timing belts were the main goal. I
wanted this to use pin-feed card stock, so an old dot-matrix printer was
also sacrificed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was without camera for most of the month, so documentation is
non-existent. Regardless, the documentation would have been something
like this: &amp;quot;!&amp;#64;#$!&amp;#64;#$ MORE EPOXY! !&amp;#64;#%!#$&amp;quot;, along with pictures of me
looking frustrated. Let's just say, this machine is a hack, on top of a
kludge, wrapped in a cob-job. We ended up with the paper-feed mechanism
from the dot-matrix printer acting as the Y axis, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.adafruit.com/products/412"&gt;a small solenoid
from adafruit&lt;/a&gt; riding along on
the X axis with a wobbly pen-holder (and some tape (and epoxy!)). This
was all hooked up to a rickety breadboard (I designed and ordered an
Arduino shield via &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://batchpcb.com"&gt;Batch PCB&lt;/a&gt;, but it didn't
arrive in time) with two &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pololu.com/catalog/product/1201"&gt;Polulu stepper
drivers&lt;/a&gt;, an Arduino, and
a simple transistor doohicky for toggling the solenoid. We ran
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/simen/grbl"&gt;grbl&lt;/a&gt; on the Arduino, and after
tracking down a bug in said code and reflashing the firmware, we were
well on our way. I learned a lot, stressed a bit, and the morning of
BarCamp we barely managed this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="/wp-uploads/2011/10/DSC_8494.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image2" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-672" src="/wp-uploads/2011/10/DSC_8494-1024x678.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it got better throughout the day, with some live on-the-scene
hacking. I managed to get a toolchain set up to get webcam input traced
and plotted thusly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/6294760604/"&gt;&lt;img alt="IMG_8267" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6039/6294760604_cbcfdc264e_z.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That toolchain starts with
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://opencv.willowgarage.com/wiki/"&gt;OpenCV&lt;/a&gt; handling the webcam,
and doing a &amp;quot;trace outlines&amp;quot; sort of procedure. From there, a PNG is
saved, converted to vectors by
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://autotrace.sourceforge.net/"&gt;autotrace&lt;/a&gt;, converted from eps to
hpgl (the language of old-timey plotters) by
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pstoedit.net/"&gt;pstoedit&lt;/a&gt;, slurped back into Python via
the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://music.columbia.edu/cmc/chiplotle/"&gt;Chiplotle HPGL
library&lt;/a&gt;, where I have a
few routines scale and optimize the tool path, and then we output some
ugly gcode and stream it to the Arduino. Phew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a bit roundabout. But it worked, and it made people smile and
wander over to talk to us... and they got some cool robo-portraits out
of it. I'll leave you with another image and video of the bot doing its
thing. A few more can be found in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/sets/72157628015314436/detail/"&gt;my flickr
gallery&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/6294232619/"&gt;&lt;img alt="IMG_8269" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6100/6294232619_e42b143249_z.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Docubot Hands-free Camera</title><link href="/docubot-hands-free-camera.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-09-28T15:05:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-09-28T15:05:00+00:00</updated><author><name>berticus</name></author><id>tag:None,2011-09-28:/docubot-hands-free-camera.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/6077141844/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DSC_6891.jpg" class="alignleft" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6080/6077141844_89382e76c4.jpg" style="width: 380px; height: 250px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/6077135434/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DSC_6888.jpg" class="alignleft" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6181/6077135434_f0893c06a4.jpg" style="width: 166px; height: 250px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely this will be my last poorly documented project: a hands-free foot
operated documentation camera. I thought it'd be handy, and I had an old
broken desk lamp kicking around, so of course, the two must be mushed
together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/6077147088/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DSC_6894.jpg" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6190/6077147088_4b3c84db77.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 333px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out with an old Canon SD1000, with
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://chdk.wikia.com/wiki/CHDK"&gt;CHDK&lt;/a&gt; installed …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/6077141844/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DSC_6891.jpg" class="alignleft" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6080/6077141844_89382e76c4.jpg" style="width: 380px; height: 250px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/6077135434/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DSC_6888.jpg" class="alignleft" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6181/6077135434_f0893c06a4.jpg" style="width: 166px; height: 250px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely this will be my last poorly documented project: a hands-free foot
operated documentation camera. I thought it'd be handy, and I had an old
broken desk lamp kicking around, so of course, the two must be mushed
together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/6077147088/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DSC_6894.jpg" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6190/6077147088_4b3c84db77.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 333px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out with an old Canon SD1000, with
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://chdk.wikia.com/wiki/CHDK"&gt;CHDK&lt;/a&gt; installed of course. For
those in the dark, CHDK is an alternate firmware that works on lots of
point and shoot cameras (not just Canon, anymore), and it lets you run
scripts, save pictures as raw files, and tweak every setting you could
ever possibly want to. It's awesome, and I needed it so I could trigger
the shutter via an external button (you basically toggle +5v on one of
the USB port pins).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/6076628007/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DSC_6902.jpg" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6205/6076628007_f98976013f.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 333px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't want to worry about running out of batteries mid-shoot, so I
printed a dummy battery at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.shapeways.com/"&gt;Shapeways&lt;/a&gt;,
ran some wires through it, then tinned and bent over the ends of them to
make some pseudo &amp;quot;terminals&amp;quot;. These went out a hole I drilled in the
battery door, through the lamp, to a simple 5v voltage regulator, wired
up straight out of the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.national.com/ds/LM/LM109.pdf"&gt;datasheet&lt;/a&gt;. This 5v source
also goes through an old lamp foot switch to the camera's USB port, for
the external trigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/6077171350/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DSC_6905.jpg" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6187/6077171350_06cb8350d0.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 333px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/6076615413/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DSC_6898.jpg" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6061/6076615413_b204a847f4.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 333px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I took to the lathe to make an adapter between the weird lamp
thread and standard camera tripod thread (1/4&amp;quot; diameter, 20 threads per
inch). I used a bit of round delrin stock, bored out the appropriate
diameters, and just cranked a bolt through rather than threading things
properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried a few test shots last night, while I put together &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mightyohm.com/blog/products/geiger-counter/"&gt;Mighty Ohm's
Geiger Counter
Kit&lt;/a&gt;. It works
pretty well, but can't really zoom in close enough to document very fine
work. Hopefully it will still be useful for documenting other tasks that
require both your hands in frame. Failing that, I'm sure there will be
other uses for a scriptable camera attached to a flexible-yet-solid
base... perhaps it will turn into a time-lapse-bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/6190441282/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DocuBot Test 1" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6147/6190441282_7da14f7397.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 375px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/6190437268/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DocuBot Test 2" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6152/6190437268_f14a3515a8.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 375px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/6190437602/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DocuBot Test 3" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6145/6190437602_041ccdbf22.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 375px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Plottopotamus</title><link href="/plottopotamus.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-09-13T22:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-09-13T22:20:00+00:00</updated><author><name>berticus</name></author><id>tag:None,2011-09-13:/plottopotamus.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been taking up quite a bit of space at Interlock lately with my new
toy, a Roland DPX-3300 pen plotter... delivered via ebay from the
magical futurepast of the early nineties. For those that are out of the
loop with the past century, pen plotters are two axis robo-thingamajigs …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been taking up quite a bit of space at Interlock lately with my new
toy, a Roland DPX-3300 pen plotter... delivered via ebay from the
magical futurepast of the early nineties. For those that are out of the
loop with the past century, pen plotters are two axis robo-thingamajigs
that basically pick up pens and draw on paper with them. They've been
replaced by wide-format inkjet printers, but they used to be quite
popular with anybody who wanted to plot out maps, blueprints, and other
large diagrams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/5937490274/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Interlock Plotty Pictures 1" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6125/5937490274_0b95dfca21.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 333px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, somehow I caught the plotter bug, even going so far as to learn
a bit of python after finding this neat library called
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://music.columbia.edu/cmc/chiplotle/"&gt;Chiplotle&lt;/a&gt; that handles
the basics of creating and streaming artwork to plotters using their
native language of HPGL. They have a mailing list where they often point
out good plotter deals on ebay, and I foolishly/accidentally purchased
perhaps the biggest flatbed plotter out there. 3x2 feet of plotting
goodness, 100 pounds of steel and stepper motors delivered to my door by
a grumpy UPS driver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/5936937271/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Interlock Plotty Pictures 2" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6009/5936937271_0e87fb9250.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 333px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After realizing it doesn't fit anywhere in my house, I brought it to
Interlock and have been tinkering with it since. The first step was to
convert old dried out plotter pens into pen holders that would allow me
to use Sharpies or other art pens with the device. That involved a quick
trip to the lathe, which I hope to document more fully in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/5936918129/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Interlock Plotty Pictures 3" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6006/5936918129_7d4e1d4a2e.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 333px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having figured out an inexpensive pen solution, I really wanted to make
drawings based on webcam input... so I trawled around the internet and
mailing lists until I could piece together a passable solution using
OpenCV's python bindings, and a series of nerdy unixy commands (convert,
autotrace, and pstoedit) to trace, mush, and output the data. You can
find the relevant code up on my &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/beardicus/ronald_toys%20"&gt;Ronald
Toys&lt;/a&gt; Github repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/5937423454/"&gt;&lt;img alt="RoboPortraits" src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6125/5937423454_df75c66a42.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 333px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having conquered such menial tasks, I decided that the default route the
plotter was taking was quite inefficient, with lots of time spent
seeking back and forth between lines. My precious robot was spending
half its time flailing due to a poorly composed hpgl file. Surely there
was a better way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/beardicus/ronald_tools%20"&gt;Tada!&lt;/a&gt; I wrote a
really dumb sort routine that attempts to minimize seeking between
lines, instead of blindly accepting the order that autotrace wrote them
in. You can see the difference in the following two time-lapse videos.
The first shows the default route that autotrace produces, and the
second is my optimized version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next step for this project: some more sophisticated drawing routines,
including some cross-hatched shading, color, and maybe even some 3D
input from a Kinect. Stop in for a Tuesday Open Night and maybe you can
be a robo-portrait guinea pig!&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>November Lightning Talks</title><link href="/november-lightning-talks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-11-08T11:19:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-11-08T11:19:00+00:00</updated><author><name>berticus</name></author><id>tag:None,2010-11-08:/november-lightning-talks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4422595768/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DSC_0313" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2706/4422595768_d141b52aa5_m.jpg" style="width: 240px; height: 160px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us this Friday, November 12th at 8pm for another stimulating night
of lightning talks at Interlock! Lightning talks are five minute(-ish)
presentations on whatever topic you're passionate about, and we try to
get through fifteen or twenty of them in a night. The event is free and
open …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4422595768/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DSC_0313" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2706/4422595768_d141b52aa5_m.jpg" style="width: 240px; height: 160px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us this Friday, November 12th at 8pm for another stimulating night
of lightning talks at Interlock! Lightning talks are five minute(-ish)
presentations on whatever topic you're passionate about, and we try to
get through fifteen or twenty of them in a night. The event is free and
open to the public, and anybody is welcome to present. We'll have some
food and beverage on hand to stimulate digestion and discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're going to present, and need to get slides situated, please show
up a little early and/or mail your slides to &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:info&amp;#64;interlockroc.org"&gt;info&amp;#64;interlockroc.org&lt;/a&gt;
sometime before the event. We encourage a wide variety of topics... not
just tech-oriented subjects. Previous talks have been about lockpicking,
homebrewing, bookbinding, artificial intelligence, basic electronics,
laser cutting, and on and on. Teach us something new!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4421833521/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DSC_0316" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4038/4421833521_746fb94c07_m.jpg" style="width: 240px; height: 160px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is our &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://maps.google.com/maps/place?cid=16733278776132858158&amp;amp;q=1115+Main+St+E,+Rochester,+NY+14609&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ved=0CFQQ-QswAw&amp;amp;ei=6R7YTL24JZLqzASk97jKCQ&amp;amp;sll=43.161954,-77.582684&amp;amp;sspn=0.006295,0.006295&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=43.166594,-77.592337&amp;amp;spn=0,0&amp;amp;z=16"&gt;Googley Maps
page&lt;/a&gt;
where you can get directions to the space. Once you get into the parking
lot of the Hungerford building, you'll want to look for Door #1 and head
down into the basement to find us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if you are on the Facebooks, please do RSVP to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.facebook.com/event.php?eid=159525710747026"&gt;our
event&lt;/a&gt; on said
site, so we can calculate pizza ingestion and seating requirements. See
you this Friday!&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Rochester 2600: Lock Pick Village</title><link href="/rochester-2600-lock-pick-village.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-11-01T17:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-11-01T17:45:00+00:00</updated><author><name>berticus</name></author><id>tag:None,2010-11-01:/rochester-2600-lock-pick-village.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Rochester 2600" src="/wp-uploads/2010/11/2600-logo.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Friday, November 5th, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rochester2600.com/"&gt;Rochester
2600&lt;/a&gt; will once again occupy the halls
of Interlock for its monthly meeting. The topic du jour will be lock
picking, with an introductory presentation from
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.com/antitree"&gt;AntiTree&lt;/a&gt;. There will be pick sets and
several types of locks on hand, so come learn a few new …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Rochester 2600" src="/wp-uploads/2010/11/2600-logo.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Friday, November 5th, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rochester2600.com/"&gt;Rochester
2600&lt;/a&gt; will once again occupy the halls
of Interlock for its monthly meeting. The topic du jour will be lock
picking, with an introductory presentation from
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.com/antitree"&gt;AntiTree&lt;/a&gt;. There will be pick sets and
several types of locks on hand, so come learn a few new tricks and enjoy
some grub from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.camspizzeria.com/locations/eastave.html"&gt;Cam's
Pizzeria&lt;/a&gt;. The
festivities start at 7:30PM.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Electronics Class Recap</title><link href="/electronics-class-recap.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-10-17T15:58:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-10-17T15:58:00+00:00</updated><author><name>berticus</name></author><id>tag:None,2010-10-17:/electronics-class-recap.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In addition to being our weekly open night, last Tuesday was the first
of five classes providing an introduction to electronic components,
circuits, and methods. Attendance was great, and gratitude goes to our
intrepid instructor, Carl, who did an excellent job of explaining these
concepts for the layperson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.camspizzeria.com/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cam's Pizzeria" src="/wp-uploads/2010/10/cams-pizzeria-small.gif" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interlock would …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In addition to being our weekly open night, last Tuesday was the first
of five classes providing an introduction to electronic components,
circuits, and methods. Attendance was great, and gratitude goes to our
intrepid instructor, Carl, who did an excellent job of explaining these
concepts for the layperson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.camspizzeria.com/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cam's Pizzeria" src="/wp-uploads/2010/10/cams-pizzeria-small.gif" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interlock would also like to extend a special thanks, from the bottom of
our stomachs, to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.camspizzeria.com/"&gt;Cam's Pizzeria&lt;/a&gt; for
providing free pizza to visitors and attendees of last week's class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="missed-the-class"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Missed The Class?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to take this course but were unable to attend the
first class, fret not! You can catch up by reading the &lt;a class="reference external" href="/wp-uploads/2010/10/basic-electronics-class-1.pdf"&gt;lecture
notes&lt;/a&gt;,
and there will be plenty of knowledgeable individuals to answer
questions after the class or during the course labs on Thursday nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course continues this Tuesday, October 19th at 8:00PM, and will go
into further detail about how each component works and how they function
within a circuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Rochester Security Summit 2010</title><link href="/rochester-security-summit-2010.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-10-16T19:09:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-10-16T19:09:00+00:00</updated><author><name>berticus</name></author><id>tag:None,2010-10-16:/rochester-security-summit-2010.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Strathallan Hotel will be home to Rochester Security Summit 2010,
taking place October 20th and 21st. This year's theme is Emerging
Threats, and will feature presentations from keynote speaker Stephen
Northcutt, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rapid7.com/"&gt;Rapid7&lt;/a&gt; security consultant
Joshua D. Abraham, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://securityjustice.com/"&gt;Security Justice&lt;/a&gt;
host Matt Neely, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dc585.info/"&gt;DC585&lt;/a&gt; organizer and friend
of Interlock …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Strathallan Hotel will be home to Rochester Security Summit 2010,
taking place October 20th and 21st. This year's theme is Emerging
Threats, and will feature presentations from keynote speaker Stephen
Northcutt, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rapid7.com/"&gt;Rapid7&lt;/a&gt; security consultant
Joshua D. Abraham, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://securityjustice.com/"&gt;Security Justice&lt;/a&gt;
host Matt Neely, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dc585.info/"&gt;DC585&lt;/a&gt; organizer and friend
of Interlock, Jason Ross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2006, Rochester Security Summit is a community focal point
for education and awareness in collaboration with higher education,
business and industry partners, held during National Cyber Security
Awareness Month. The Summit features speakers and panels to help educate
area security and IT professionals, business managers, organizations and
our community on how to protect information systems and data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interlock information security members Mark Manning and Jeremy Turner
will be in attendance. Look for our table during the event on Wednesday
and &lt;em&gt;anrwntaosvtisfw&lt;/em&gt; for a free drink ticket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the event, visit the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rochestersecurity.org/"&gt;Rochester Security
Summit&lt;/a&gt; website.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Open Mate, Beta 2</title><link href="/open-mate-beta-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-04-17T22:26:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-04-17T22:26:00+00:00</updated><author><name>berticus</name></author><id>tag:None,2010-04-17:/open-mate-beta-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4480074334"&gt;http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4480074334&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two long weeks ago, we finally scrounged the equipment and ingredients
necessary to iterate &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.hackpittsburgh.org/brewing-open-mate-soda"&gt;Hack Pittsburgh's Open Mate
recipe&lt;/a&gt;.
Personally, I hadn't heard of this odd &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Club-Mate"&gt;Club
Mate&lt;/a&gt; beverage until I saw
the recipe, but -- being a homebrewer -- I couldn't help but to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4480074334"&gt;http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4480074334&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two long weeks ago, we finally scrounged the equipment and ingredients
necessary to iterate &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.hackpittsburgh.org/brewing-open-mate-soda"&gt;Hack Pittsburgh's Open Mate
recipe&lt;/a&gt;.
Personally, I hadn't heard of this odd &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Club-Mate"&gt;Club
Mate&lt;/a&gt; beverage until I saw
the recipe, but -- being a homebrewer -- I couldn't help but to order a
case (for comparison purposes only, of course) and hunt down some &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yerba_mat%C3%A9"&gt;yerba
maté&lt;/a&gt; and caffeine
powder of my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With said ingredients in hand, we put three gallons of water on the hot
plate during one of our Tuesday open nights (come visit!), and proceeded
to spend three hours hovering around the kitchen area, waiting for it to
get anywhere near boiling. The tea was brewed, sugared, cooled, and
kegged with the following specifications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ingredients"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 gallons of water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3oz yerba mate tea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2c sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;juice of 0.5 lemons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5t citric acid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4480069168"&gt;http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4480069168&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4480092698"&gt;http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4480092698&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="procedure"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Procedure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bring water to just under a boil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add tea to water (I put the tea in a big homebrewing grain bag,
effectively creating a huge teabag)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;steep for six minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove tea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add sugar, lemon juice, citric acid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cool, pour into a keg, carbonate at 20psi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll notice we skipped the caffeine this time. Personally, I'm more
concerned with flavor than (added) stimulants, so I never bothered
tracking down a scale sensitive enough to measure out one or two grams
of powder. Feel free to add that in when you're adding the sugar (check
out &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.hackpittsburgh.org/brewing-open-mate-soda"&gt;Hack Pittsburgh's
recipe&lt;/a&gt; for the
correct measurements and warnings).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4525162394"&gt;http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4525162394&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="yum"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Yum?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finally got to do some beta tasting this past Thursday, and all
testers agreed that it was yummy and pretty faithful to the original
product. I have since sat down for a more in-depth side-by-side
comparison (not double-blinded, mind you), and I feel our recipe --
although quite tasty -- has come up a bit short compared to the real
deal. The sweetness is spot on, but there is a complexity and depth to
the tea flavor that is missing in our beverage. So I think we'll try
some things differently next time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding lemon was a mistake: I was hoping to avoid uncommon
ingredients like citric acid, but alas, you should go out and get
some (cream of tartar was a pretty popular substitute in old-timey
ginger beer recipes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more citric acid: fizzy tea is pretty dull without a bit of acid
zing. We should probably at least double it next time, but further
experimentation is in order&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;increase the tea input: I'm hoping part of the depth-of-flavor
difference is merely a matter of strength&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caramelize some of the sugar first: Club Mate has added coloring.
Hopefully caramelizing some of the sugar will make Open Mate less
pale, and also improve flavor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any other ideas? I can't wait to work through our first three gallons,
so we can start brewing the next version. Bottoms up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4524528227"&gt;http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4524528227&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Hello World.</title><link href="/hello-world-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-12-02T13:10:00+00:00</published><updated>2009-12-02T13:10:00+00:00</updated><author><name>berticus</name></author><id>tag:None,2009-12-02:/hello-world-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's true. We're starting up a hackerspace in Rochester, New York.
Please check out &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.meetup.com/Rochester-Hackerspace"&gt;our Meetup
page&lt;/a&gt; if you're already
convinced you need to join us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For everybody else, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="/pages/about.html"&gt;about
page&lt;/a&gt; is a good place to get up
to speed with what's going on. In summary: we're creating a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's true. We're starting up a hackerspace in Rochester, New York.
Please check out &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.meetup.com/Rochester-Hackerspace"&gt;our Meetup
page&lt;/a&gt; if you're already
convinced you need to join us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For everybody else, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="/pages/about.html"&gt;about
page&lt;/a&gt; is a good place to get up
to speed with what's going on. In summary: we're creating a space in
which we plan to make cool stuff, teach, learn, and race robots. We've
already found a suitably grungy spot to inhabit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4147395075/"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Final Space 1" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2569/4147395075_8b5d67e5d7.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 333px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4147399201/"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Final Space 2" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2749/4147399201_3d619df561.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 333px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which should be cleaned out and fixed up (by the landlords, thankfully)
by early January. In the meantime we're having some really productive
meetings every Tuesday night, and would love to see more potential
members show up to give their input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/4152703689/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DSC_8749" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2778/4152703689_715603a0fe.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 333px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can't make the meetings, there are many options for getting in
touch with us. I recommend &lt;a class="reference external" href="irc://irc.slashnet.org#interlock"&gt;our IRC
channel&lt;/a&gt;, but you'll find more
social-networky stuff on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="/pages/contact.html"&gt;contact
page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>