<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>A Pelican Blog - Classes, Projects</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/classes-projects.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2011-09-07T09:43:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Android Hacking</title><link href="/android-hacking.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-09-07T09:43:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-09-07T09:43:00+00:00</updated><author><name>antitree</name></author><id>tag:None,2011-09-07:/android-hacking.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="/wp-uploads/2011/09/android_hack_logo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image0" class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-520" src="/wp-uploads/2011/09/android_hack_logo-150x150.jpg" style="width: 150px; height: 150px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Android right now makes up 52% of the smartphone market share
and a third of the tablets. I've been focused on Android lately and
wanted to do an&amp;nbsp;introduction&amp;nbsp;to the hackability of these devices.&amp;nbsp;From a
security perspective, Android offers some interesting opportunities:
rooting your phone, hacking an app …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="/wp-uploads/2011/09/android_hack_logo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image0" class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-520" src="/wp-uploads/2011/09/android_hack_logo-150x150.jpg" style="width: 150px; height: 150px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Android right now makes up 52% of the smartphone market share
and a third of the tablets. I've been focused on Android lately and
wanted to do an&amp;nbsp;introduction&amp;nbsp;to the hackability of these devices.&amp;nbsp;From a
security perspective, Android offers some interesting opportunities:
rooting your phone, hacking an app, or malware analysis. For the
hardware hackers, Google and others are offering hardware tools that can
plug into your Android device to enable use them for your hardware
projects. If you're interested in the creative path, it's really easy to
get started doing app development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rooting:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rooting your device offers the user full control of the device to allow
to change the version of the operating system, install or uninstall any
apps you'd like, and in some cases gain access to features that would
otherwise be locked out by the carrier. If none of those interest you,
the geek cred alone may be good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rooting is nothing more than a&amp;nbsp;privilege&amp;nbsp;escalation attack. You are
granted standard user access to your phone but you'd like to escalate to
root level&amp;nbsp;privileges. Android, being built on top of Linux follows the
common practice of granting root only when necessary to your device's
operations. There are a bunch of attack vectors like exploiting a
service running as root, exploiting a file that has root access,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;App Hacking:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of fun stuff you can do to hack an Android app. It's
originally coded in Java and although Android runs it's own Java
environment called Dalvik VM, an app can be decompiled from it's byte
code to Java class files. From there you can do some reverse engineering
to take a look at how the app operates. With a little luck and skill,
you can recompile a modified version of the app. I'm not going to go too
deep into this idea but if you're interested, I'll be doing a
presentation at this years &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rochestersecurity.org"&gt;Rochester Security
Summit&lt;/a&gt; that will give you the
tools to do this analysis yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malware:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the security guys now, malware analysis is a fun way to get a peek
into how the bad guys work. Android is in a battle with malware usually
available in alternative markets. Nasty apps like &amp;quot;Nickispy&amp;quot; will steal
your personal information and even record your calls to upload them back
to a server. Some will root your device and install a backdoor like the
latest variant of DroidKungFu. With some tools and some different
analysis techniques, you can perform the analysis yourself. Jason Ross
will also be presenting this year at RSS on this topic if you're
interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware Hacking:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this years Google IO, they announced the release of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.google.com/events/io/2011/sessions/android-open-accessory-api-and-development-kit-adk.html"&gt;Android
Development
Kit&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;which
is a bridge between your Android device and your hardware projects.
Imagine controlling an Arduino with a touch screen interface or using
the sensors from your phone to control a robot. As a cheap alternative
to the $300+ kit, Sparkfun has created the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sparkfun.com/products/10748"&gt;Android
IOIO&lt;/a&gt;, pronounced yoyo. This
is what my next project will include with a little help from the robot
crew at Interlock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;App Development:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If programming or art is your thing, or you want to make your next
million dollars on an Angry Birds killer, you can get started developing
apps on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://market.android.com/publish"&gt;Android Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;
for $25. This gets you an account to upload your app to the public
directory and it will show up on thousands of people's phones. The
Android SDK along with the Eclipse plugins make it pretty easy to
develop without too much programming knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Android At Interlock:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming months, along with all the other changes, we're planning
on doing an Android workshop at the space. Depending on the interest it
may be related to rooting or application development.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>