<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>A Pelican Blog - Events, Security</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/events-security.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2012-04-19T14:48:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>New Lockpicking Club: Rochester TOOOL</title><link href="/new-lockpicking-club-rochester-toool.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-04-19T14:48:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-04-19T14:48:00+00:00</updated><author><name>antitree</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-04-19:/new-lockpicking-club-rochester-toool.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tonight (Thursday) a new club will be using the Rochester hackerspace as
a meeting ground for its first event. The Rochester TOOOL (yes three
O's) chapter is starting up organized by Jason Ross. What's a Jason Ross
and what's a TOOOL right? Jason is the newest Interlock member and comes …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tonight (Thursday) a new club will be using the Rochester hackerspace as
a meeting ground for its first event. The Rochester TOOOL (yes three
O's) chapter is starting up organized by Jason Ross. What's a Jason Ross
and what's a TOOOL right? Jason is the newest Interlock member and comes
from a background in security - computer security, network security,
physical security.. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://i.qkme.me/7dck.jpg"&gt;secure all the
things!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="why-lock-picking"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Lock Picking?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="/wp-uploads/2012/04/a_misery1990.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image0" class="size-full wp-image-861 aligncenter" src="/wp-uploads/2012/04/a_misery1990.jpg" style="width: 590px; height: 403px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's happened to the best of us, your bloodshot eyes open to find that
you've been strapped to a bed with handcuffs again. What do you do to
get out? Call for help? Wait until the lady comes back to break your
legs like in Misery? No, you know how the locking mechanism works on a
pair of handcuffs and you shim your way out and escape through the
window to freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lock picking is learning about how locks work which turns them into a
puzzle. The number of pins in a tumbler tells you how difficult the lock
is. What does it mean when a pair of handcuffs are double locked? What
are security pins? What's the difference between a wafer lock and a pin
tumbler? If you have these questions, TOOOL is the group to talk with to
have them answered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="toool"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;TOOOL&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.toool.us"&gt;&lt;img alt="image1" class="aligncenter" src="http://toool.us/images/toool_logo_lg.gif" style="width: 485px; height: 176px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.toool.us"&gt;TOOOL&lt;/a&gt;is The Open Organization Of
Lockpickers. These guys love to learn and teach about locks, lock
picking, and physical security. The difference between TOOOL and a
normal locksmith, is first they don't do it for money, second, they
exchange information about locks and lock picking openly, and third,
they have more of a sense of humor than your standard locksmith. To
become a locksmith, normally you'd have to learn through an
apprenticeship. TOOOL on the other hand will be giving presentations to
the community, teaching people how to pick locks, and helping spread the
knowledge about lock picking openly to the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="legality"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Legality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is having a pair of lock picks legal? Is it against the law to know how
to lock pick? What if TSA finds a set of lock picks in your bag?? These
are all boring, but serious questions that TOOOL will answer. Here's a
hint, do you think Interlock would promote illegal activity on their
blog?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-to-expect-at-the-meeting"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What to expect at the meeting:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="/wp-uploads/2012/04/2011-05-07_16-57-041.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image2" class="alignright size-full wp-image-868" src="/wp-uploads/2012/04/2011-05-07_16-57-041.jpg" style="width: 292px; height: 478px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The meeting is open to the public and is meant to be the first
of future meetings. There will be a presentation of some kind related to
lock picking and a lot of discussion about how future meetings will
happen. The organization requires that you become a member in order to
keep up to date on the groups activities but there will also be public
non-member, public meetings in the future. If you can't come to
tonight's meeting but you're interested in learning about how the group
works, you can email &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:algorythm%20at%20the%20gmails%20dot%20come"&gt;Jason
Ross&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rochester TOOOL Chapter meeting starts at 7pm on 4/19 at Interlock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content></entry></feed>