<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>A Pelican Blog - phyereneyce</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/phyereneyce.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2013-12-03T21:08:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Earring Display/Storage</title><link href="/earring-displaystorage.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-12-03T21:08:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-12-03T21:08:00+00:00</updated><author><name>phyereneyce</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-12-03:/earring-displaystorage.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have an affinity for jewelry, I'll admit it. &amp;nbsp;I'm a girl, so I feel
it's okay. &amp;nbsp;I have a couple of jewelry boxes already, but some things
are difficult to store. &amp;nbsp;Like most women with a thing for jewelry, I
have more earrings than I know what to do …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have an affinity for jewelry, I'll admit it. &amp;nbsp;I'm a girl, so I feel
it's okay. &amp;nbsp;I have a couple of jewelry boxes already, but some things
are difficult to store. &amp;nbsp;Like most women with a thing for jewelry, I
have more earrings than I know what to do with. &amp;nbsp;It had gotten to the
point where I no longer had room in my jewelry box for any new pieces,
and it was becoming more than a little difficult to sort through what I
had, despite having organized them into different spaces in the built in
storage tray in the jewelry box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long story short, it was time for a change,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to make myself a earring storage and display device that I
could set out on the top of my dresser, that would allow me enough room
to hold all of my current collection, as well as expand it and not have
to develop a new storage system anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer came in the form of upcycling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went on Craigslist and looked for used windows for sale. &amp;nbsp;I found a
guy who lived not too far from me who had a whole stash of used windows
that he had removed from his home as part of a remodeling project. &amp;nbsp;I
went to see him, had an awesome conversation with him, and bought
several windows from him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose one of the long, slim windows to use for this project. &amp;nbsp;This
particular window measures approximately 40&amp;quot; x 18&amp;quot;. &amp;nbsp;I removed the storm
pane from it, brushed off the loose paint with a stiff bristle paint
brush, and lightly cleaned the glass (I say lightly because I wanted to
keep the rustic look it had. &amp;nbsp;I didn't want it to look overly done up or
commercialized.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step was a quick trip to Home Depot to buy a roll of window
screening and some upholstery nails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my supply run, I came back to Interlock and got started in
earnest. &amp;nbsp;I will fully admit that I did not follow any safety protocols
for this project. &amp;nbsp;I wasn't wearing safety glasses, steel toed shoes,
gloves, a hard hat, or ear protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I cut the screen to size with a dull pair of tin snips I had
laying around, and propped the window on a padded desk chair to nail the
screening on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used a basic claw hammer to attach the screening to the wooden window
frame. &amp;nbsp;I was actually a bit surprised at how easy it was. &amp;nbsp;I tacked one
of the long sides on first, then stretched the screening tight across
the frame and tacked on the opposite long side. &amp;nbsp;I stood the window up
on the floor to attach the short side and then trimmed off the excess
with my snips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the newly screened window home and placed it on top of my
dresser, anchoring it in place to protect from feline related
accidents/crashes by placing one of my jewelry boxes in front on if and
looping a pair of swimming flippers I have hanging from the attached
mirror on my dresser over the top corner. &amp;nbsp;Improvised solutions people,
they work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once it was in place, I hung each pair of hook backed earrings I own
onto the screening, setting their backs aside into a small bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some pictures of the finished product in place, and covered in
earrings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2989.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="100_2989" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1604" src="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2989-300x225.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 225px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2988.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="100_2988" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1603" src="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2988-300x225.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 225px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2987.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="100_2987" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1602" src="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2987-300x225.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 225px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2985.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="100_2985" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1601" src="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2985-300x225.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 225px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2983.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="100_2983" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1600" src="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2983-300x225.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 225px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here are some close-ups of the tacks attaching the screen to the
window frame:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2992.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="100_2992" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1607" src="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2992-225x300.jpg" style="width: 225px; height: 300px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2991.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="100_2991" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1606" src="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2991-300x225.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 225px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2990.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="100_2990" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1605" src="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2990-225x300.jpg" style="width: 225px; height: 300px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All said, it took about 20 minutes to make, and 20 minutes to fill up
with my collection. &amp;nbsp;I have plenty of room to expand into as my
collection grows, I can move the whole thing pretty easily, and if I
wanted to turn the whole thing 90○ and set it on the floor, propped
against the wall, I wouldn't even have to take the earring off and put
them back on, they will just rotate with the window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the total cost of this project was just under $10, so I think it
was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can do this same thing with a window with no glass, but I like that
the panes are still in it, it adds a certain je ne sais quoi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you decide to replicate this process, please be careful. &amp;nbsp;If you
don't know what you're doing, or aren't sure if you know what you're
doing, ask for help from someone in the know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Craigslist Hunting!&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Tape Painting</title><link href="/tape-painting.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-12-03T20:17:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-12-03T20:17:00+00:00</updated><author><name>phyereneyce</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-12-03:/tape-painting.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in my online travels, I came across a nifty idea that seemed
relatively simple to pull off. &amp;nbsp;It's called tape painting. &amp;nbsp;The idea is
that you apply pieces of tape to a blank canvas, in any manner you want,
then paint the canvas, again, in any manner you want …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in my online travels, I came across a nifty idea that seemed
relatively simple to pull off. &amp;nbsp;It's called tape painting. &amp;nbsp;The idea is
that you apply pieces of tape to a blank canvas, in any manner you want,
then paint the canvas, again, in any manner you want. &amp;nbsp;After you're done
painting, you remove the paint to reveal spaces of black canvas
interspersed with your painting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the blank canvas I started with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2677.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="blank canvas" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1595" src="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2677-300x225.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 225px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked it up, like all my canvas's at Ollie's here in Rochester.
&amp;nbsp;Hopefully, it goes without saying that you remove the plastic and label
that it comes wrapped in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to apply the tape. &amp;nbsp;You can do this with just about any
masking-type tape. &amp;nbsp;I chose painters tape because that's what I had on
hand. &amp;nbsp;You can apply the tape in any pattern you like. &amp;nbsp;I chose a
geometric patter, making sure to wrap the tape all the way around the
edges and on to the back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2675.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="100_2675" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1593" src="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2675-300x225.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 225px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the tape is applied, the painting can commence. &amp;nbsp;This, of course,
is the funnest step. &amp;nbsp;I typically only work with acrylic paint because
it's cheap, easy to work with, easy to obtain, easy to clean, and can be
applied with a variety of techniques. &amp;nbsp;I decided to go with an abstract
theme because this was my first attempt with this kind of art, and when
it comes to abstract, there is no wrong way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, I chose some colors, threw them on a palette, and then
applied them to the canvas at random. &amp;nbsp;You paint right over the tape as
if it weren't even there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I neglected to take a picture of this step, but I'm sure
you can use you're imagination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After painting the canvas, making sure to extend the paint onto the
sides of the canvas, remove the tape while the paint is still wet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure when you remove the tape, since most of it will be stuck
together, that you don't allow the wet paint on the tape to touch the
wet paint of the canvas or you will end up with smearing that you did
not anticipate in planning the chaos of your abstraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the finished product:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2678.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="100_2678" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1597" src="{filename}wp-uploads/2013/12/100_2678-300x225.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 225px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have the ability to plan ahead, you should attach the picture
hangers before painting, but if you chronically forget that step as I
do, wait until the painting dries, then lay it on a towel or other
padded surface to avoid scratches, and attach the hardware to the back.
&amp;nbsp;I typically use hardware that can be found in any picture hanging kit
from the dollar store or other reasonably cheap retail store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is true with almost anything, you can customize this project in any
way you want. &amp;nbsp;More tape, less tape, defined pattern, no pattern,
abstract painting, realistic painting, whatever you want. &amp;nbsp;The point is
to have fun and create a unique piece of art for very little cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Painting!&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>